Laya A

Cluster HR Manager - Velammal New

Chennai, Tamil Nadu - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Laya-A/74af8dc044f3fa7f

 $\bullet$  A competent HR Manager professional with over 10+ years of rich experience

across all domains of human resource management.

- Demonstrated expertise to work in sync with senior management team to integrate the human resource function within the organisation.
- Carrying experience in the new line of businesses, high growth operations and

restructuring.

 $\bullet$  Proven skill set in transforming & harmonizing complex and obscure ideas into an

easily assimilable plan.

• Exemplified leading from the front, time & again and inculcated a feeling of

motivation and constant work towards the attainment of the firm's goal.

• Adept in performance assessment, recruitment, induction process, compensation

management, employee welfare planning, employee retention, employee motivation, grievance handling, time office management, team management & amp;

office administration.

ullet A proactive professional with outstanding communication, interpersonal and

relationship management skills along with an ability to communicate effectively with personnel

at all levels within the organisation.

• Ensuring continuity as well as effective delivery of human resource functional services.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Cluster HR Manager

Velammal New - Chennai, Tamil Nadu -

February 2017 to Present

Cluster Manager

Velammal new gen park -

February 2017 to Present

### RESPONSIBILITIES

TALENTACQUISITION

ullet Enhancing the manpower plan in sync with the expansion strategies for all LOBs in order to

formulate new hiring strategies.

- ullet Implementing innovative ways to engage probable candidates for future expansion.
- Curbing average turnaround time of recruitment by smart measures at relatively lesser cost.
- Driving campus recruitment at elite business, law and engineering colleges with an intent to

hire the best of the best.

 $\bullet$  Leading internal hiring & guiding manpower forms on sourcing the best talents against

the vacant positions.

ullet Strategizing human resource requirements in consultation with the various

https://www.indeed.com/r/Laya-A/74af8dc044f3fa7f?isid=rex-download&ikw=download-top&co=IN

departmental heads followed by conducting selection interviews for shortlisted candidates.

- Keeping an eye on the latest hiring trends in the industry and implementing them.
- Coaching team members on effectively creating assessment and interview rating sheet.
- Streamlining interview processes, managing recruitment tracker, screening of resumes, reference check, background verification, document verification and

closing the position post successful salary negotiation.

### COMPENSATION MANAGEMENT

- Devising a wage model to reach compensation goals of the organization.
- Developing salary grid in sync with the organisational hierarchy to inculcate concord in the system.
- Drafting, designing as well as implementing attractive incentives plan to motivate staffs across
- all levels in the organisation with an intent to accelerate the revenue by optimising the degree
- of enthusiasm nestled in the work culture.
- ${\color{blue} \bullet}$  Examining and analysing the industry to strive equilibrium among internal equity, external

equity, compliance and other objectives of pay model.

 $\bullet$  Designing reward and recognition plan for sales and marketing employees as an attempt to

acknowledge their efforts towards the accomplishment of the organisational goals.

Centre Head Manager HR and Admin

Kinder - Cherthala, KERALA, IN -

November 2015 to January 2017

HR Manager

Leonine Info solutions -

June 2012 to November 2015

Process Associate@ Infosys

HR SPOC - Bengaluru, Karnataka -

May 2011 to June 2012

Bangalore, India

EDUCATION

B.B.A in UIT

Kerala University

2008

SKILLS

HR (9 years), COMPENSATION (1 year), RECRUITMENT (1 year), DETAIL ORIENTED (Less than 1 year), DOCUMENTATION (Less than 1 year)

# ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

#### CORE COMPETENCIES

- Performance Management
- Recruitment & Retention
- Training & Development
- HR Policies & Procedures
- Employee Exit
- Confidential Record Keeping
- HR Department Start-up
- Event Management
- On-boarding, Orientation & amp; Induction
- Employee Counselling
- Attendance & Leave Management
- Team Building and Morale building
- Process Documentation
- Payroll & Compensation

# TECHNICAL EXPERTISE

- Well versed with Microsoft Office (Word, Excel & Power Point)
- Microsoft Project
- Lotus, outlook and internet job portal applications.

# PERSONAGE ELEMENTS

- Analytical & Critical thinking
- Compliant & Adaptive
- Detail Oriented
- Flexible
- Honest & Hardworking
- Leadership
- Logical
- Versatile
- · Work Ethic